Hello my name is David Brown and this is a pronunciation class. Hi David. I'm
大家好，我叫戴维·布朗，这是一堂发音课。你好，戴维老师。我
fine thank you. How are you? I'm doing great. Thank you. Thank you. Welcome. Thank
很好，谢谢。您怎么样？我非常好。谢谢。谢谢。欢迎。
Thank you, David. Are you ready for your lesson today? Yes. All right. All right. Well we
谢谢您，戴维老师。您准备好上今天的课了吗？是的。好的。好的。那么我们
can practice this lesson that I see that you selected. We have this short
可以练习一下我看到您选择的这节课的内容。我们有这个短
i sound and then this long e sound the short i sound is like /ɪ/ and then the
i 音和这个长 e 音。短 i 音听起来像 /ɪ/，然后
long e sound is like /iː/, right? Okay. This is important for us to master because it
长 e 音听起来像 /iː/，对吗？好的。这对我们来说掌握起来很重要，因为它
can cause confusion for native English speakers and it's a really
可能会给英语母语者造成困惑，而且这确实是
commonly mispronounced pair. So we have some examples here. Some funny
一对经常被读错的音。我们这里有一些例子。一些有趣的
examples. We have fill and feel, sit and seat, chip and
例子。我们有 fill 和 feel，sit 和 seat，chip 和
cheap. This one is bit. This one is beat, beat, ship and this one is sheep. This
cheap。这个是 bit。这个是 beat, beat, ship，而这个是 sheep。这个
is lid and this one is lead. All right. So we need to know the difference
是 lid，而这个是 lead。好的。所以我们需要知道 /ɪ/ 音和
between the /ɪ/ sound and the /iː/ sound, the /ɪ/ sound and the /iː/ sound. Okay. The
/iː/ 音之间的区别，/ɪ/ 音和 /iː/ 音。好的。
short /ɪ/ versus the /iː/ sounds. So this is what we'll practice in today's lesson. Two
短 /ɪ/ 音与长 /iː/ 音的区别。这就是我们今天课上要练习的内容。两个
different sounds. For example, what is this? This is ship*, ship, very good. And this
不同的音。例如，这是什么？这是 ship*, ship，非常好。而这个，
one, these are, these are sheep. These are sheep, right? Regular plural noun. So we're
这些是 sheep。这些是 sheep，对吧？规则复数名词。所以我们
looking at two English sounds that can be a little bit tricky but are very, very
正在学习两个可能有点棘手但对于清晰发音非常非常重要的
important for clear speaking. We want to understand and be understood and this can
英语发音。我们希望理解并被理解，而这会
impact our comprehension. So it can change the meaning of words. We have this one
影响我们的理解能力。所以它可以改变词语的意思。我们有这个词
which is ship and this one which is cheap and that is just one example. So today we
ship，还有这个词 cheap，这只是一个例子。所以今天我们
have two objectives here. I'd like for you to listen to these objectives. Today you
这里有两个目标。我希望你们听一下这些目标。今天你们
will learn to hear the difference between /ɪ/ and /iː/ and say /ɪ/ and /iː/ more clearly. Let's
将学会听辨 /ɪ/ 和 /iː/ 之间的区别，并更清晰地发出 /ɪ/ 和 /iː/ 的音。让我们
try this. Can you repeat it for me? /ɪ/. Now, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. Awesome. And so we have a little
试试这个。你能跟我重复一遍吗？/ɪ/。现在，/iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/。太棒了。所以我们这里有一个小小的
activity here to practice. I said that you would need something like a stick and something
练习活动。我说过你们需要像一根棍子和一块积木
like a block. So I have a colored pencil and one of my daughter's blocks. Do you have
这样的东西。所以我有一支彩色铅笔和我女儿的一块积木。你有什么
something? Okay, yes, yes, I have something. Okay, okay, like this. Alright, so let's
东西吗？好的，是的，是的，我有一些东西。好的，好的，像这样。好吧，那么让我们
imagine that we have the /ɪ/ sound and it's like tapping a block. Okay, right? So tap /ɪ/
想象我们发出 /ɪ/ 音，就像敲击一块积木一样。好的，对吧？所以敲击 /ɪ/
your block, say /ɪ/. Now we have the /iː/ sound which is longer. You can imagine that you have
你的积木，说 /ɪ/。现在我们有 /iː/ 音，它更长。你可以想象你拿着
your pencil and you're dragging it against something, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/. Good, /iː/. Alright, so
你的铅笔在某个东西上拖动，/iː/, /iː/, /iː/。很好，/iː/。好吧，那么
listen again, /ɪ/, /ɪ/ /iː/, /iː/. Notice that your jaw changes. So you have your tongue in a position
再听一遍，/ɪ/, /ɪ/ /iː/, /iː/。注意你的下巴会变化。你的舌头在口腔中的位置，
of your mouth higher for one than the other. It's all about the position of your tongue
发一个音时比另一个音时更高。这完全取决于你舌头在口腔中的位置，
in your mouth, /iː/ sound versus the /ɪ/, which is a little bit more relaxed. Okay. Do you hear
/iː/ 音对比 /ɪ/ 音，/ɪ/ 音更放松一些。好的。你听出
the difference? Yes. Okay, excellent. So the short i, the /ɪ/ sound is a little bit
区别了吗？是的。好的，非常好。所以短 i 音，即 /ɪ/ 音，与 /iː/ 音
different than the /iː/ sound, the /iː/ is more, and it's /iː/ with the tongue higher up. We have
有点不同，/iː/ 音更……，而且是舌头位置更高的 /iː/ 音。我们发
the /ɪ/ sound with the jaw lower down, /iː/, you see my mouth, /iː/, alright? Okay, now you
/ɪ/ 音时下巴更低一些，/iː/，看我的嘴型，/iː/，对吧？好的，现在你
don't want to say /ɛ/, and this is, we have the /ɛ/ sounds like lead (metal), and we have the /ɪ/ sound
不想发 /ɛ/ 音，这是，我们有像 lead (金属 - jīnshǔ) 这样的 /ɛ/ 音，我们有像 lid 这样的 /ɪ/ 音，
like lid, and then we have the /iː/ sound like lead (to guide). And all of this depends on the position
然后我们有像 lead (引导 - yǐndǎo) 这样的 /iː/ 音。所有这些都取决于你舌头在口腔中的位置。
of your tongue in your mouth. We have /ɛ/, /ɪ/, and /iː/. Repeat after me, /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/   /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/
我们有 /ɛ/, /ɪ/, 和 /iː/。跟我重复，/ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/   /ɛ/, /ɪ/, /iː/
/iː/. Very good. Alright, so there are some differences in these sounds depending on the position
/iː/。非常好。好的，所以根据你舌头或下巴的位置，这些音会有一些差异。
of your tongue or jaw. So your mouth needs to be a little bit more open than with the
所以你的嘴需要比发西班牙语的 /i/ 音时张得更开一点。
/i/ in Spanish. Your lips are relaxed, not smiling and not tight. So with the /ɪ/, it's like
你的嘴唇是放松的，不是微笑状，也不是紧绷的。所以对于 /ɪ/ 音，它更像是
this little bit more and it is just /ɪ/, /ɪ/, right? Not /ɛ/. The tongue is a little high, a
这样一点点，它只是 /ɪ/, /ɪ/, 对吧？不是 /ɛ/。舌头位置略高，略微
little to the front, and you'll need to relax your tongue a little. And it's a quick, a short
靠前，你需要稍微放松你的舌头。它是一个快速、短促的
quick sound like a little tap in the block sound, right? Okay. Feel it, relaxed. So try
音，就像轻轻敲击积木的声音，对吧？好的。感受它，放松。那么试着
making this sound yourself. You can mute it. Try making this sound yourself again. Let
自己发出这个音。你可以静音。再试着自己发出这个音。让
me hear you. Okay, /ɪ/, /iː/ And then /ɪ/, and /iː/, very good. Excellent. Okay. Alright.
我听听。好的，/ɪ/, /iː/ 然后是 /ɪ/, 和 /iː/, 非常好。太棒了。好的。好吧。
And just a little bit of this practice can make a big difference. So now I want you to
仅仅这一点点练习就能产生很大的不同。那么现在我希望你
show me... you can use a mirror or you can use the camera too. If you're too shy to use the
给我看看……你可以用镜子，也可以用摄像头。如果你太害羞不愿用摄像头，
camera, that's okay if you want to use a mirror. So look at your mouth in the camera.
用镜子也可以。那么看着摄像头里你的嘴。
Okay. Like this. You can see /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, not /ɛ/, but /ɪ/... /ɪ/ , and /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, perfect.
好的。像这样。你可以看到 /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, /ɪ/, 不是 /ɛ/, 而是 /ɪ/... /ɪ/ , 还有 /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, /iː/, 完美。
Alright, so you have the mouth, which has the lips spread wide, like a rubber band, for
好的，所以你的嘴，嘴唇张得很宽，像拉开的橡皮筋一样，用于发
the /iː/ sounds, and it's high into the front, and you can feel a little bit of tension. So
/iː/ 音，舌位高而靠前，你能感觉到一点点紧张。所以
we have the, this one, which is the /iː/ sound, this is /ɪt/, and this one is /iːt/, right? Right.
我们有，这个，也就是 /iː/ 音，这是 /ɪt/，而这个是 /iːt/，对吧？对。
It's a long, stretch sound, like pulling something. So you can imagine for the /iː/ sound
它是一个长的、拉伸的音，像拉东西一样。所以你可以想象发 /iː/ 音时，
that you have, like rubber bands pulling in the corner of your mouth for this one.
就像有橡皮筋拉着你的嘴角一样。
So you can see this in the image here. You have the, /ɪ/ sounds here, which is the center
所以你可以在这里的图片中看到这个。这里有 /ɪ/ 音，它在中间
in the front. The jaw is mid to close, and it's relaxed. And then the /iː/ sound is more spread
靠前的位置。下巴半合拢，是放松的。然后 /iː/ 音时嘴唇咧得更开。
apart. It's a little bit more closed, and the tongue is a little higher up. That's a
嘴巴闭合度更高一些，舌头也更靠上一些。
good job. Alright, so let's practice some of these. Here's an activity for us. You've got
做得很好。好的，那么我们来练习一些。这里有一个活动。你已经拿到了
your block and your pencil or pen, or whatever, or stick. Okay. So when you, when I say,
你的积木和铅笔或钢笔，或者随便什么，或者棍子。好的。那么当你，当我读，
or when, and when you say a word that has this short /ɪ/ sound, I want you to tap the block.
或者当，当你读到一个包含这个短 /ɪ/ 音的词时，我希望你敲一下积木。
Okay. And then when it has a long /iː/ sound, and then I want you to slide your stick. You ready?
好的。然后当它包含长 /iː/ 音时，我希望你滑动你的棍子。准备好了吗？
I'm ready. All right. So ship. Repeat, ship, ship.
我准备好了。好的。那么 ship。重复，ship, ship。
Uh-huh. Ship. Ship. Get. Bed. Bed. Beats. Beats. Ship. Ship. And ship.
嗯哼。Ship. Ship. Get. Bed. Bed. Beats. Beats. Ship. Ship. 还有 ship.
Sheep. Good. Sit. Good. Fill. Feel. Feel. Good. All right. We can practice a little bit more with this
Sheep. 很好。Sit. 很好。Fill. Feel. Feel. 很好。好的。我们可以用这个 /ɪ/ 音再多练习一下。
/ɪ/ sound.
/ɪ/ 音。